[{"id": "600240d14be4723ccac22169", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dances with Wolves\"?", "answer": "Michael Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19a", "question": "What was the name of the official 1972 Summer Olympics logo?", "answer": "Bright Sun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ffbaa3a3a814d89068c68", "question": "What is Freddie Mercury's birth name?", "answer": "Farrokh Bulsara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e38d2e1f6c8a670a7957c59", "question": "What is the maximum current of an LASCR (Light Activated Silicon Controlled Rectifier)?", "answer": "3 amps", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b084", "question": "What object did Ben Franklin attach to the end of a kite string to prove that lightning is electricity?", "answer": "A metal key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07c", "question": "In which sport would you expect to find a Short Stop?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929c", "question": "Apart from the piano, what other musical instrument does Dr. Sheldon Cooper from the TV show \"The Big Band Theory\"?", "answer": "The theramin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c664", "question": "Phobos and Deimos are moons of what planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636aea967692ea851899a1", "question": "On July 4th of what year was the Declaration of Independence adopted?", "answer": "1776", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be1d", "question": "What is the setting for the video game Fallout 3?", "answer": "Capital Wasteland/Washington D.C.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab4f", "question": "What city is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?", "answer": "Pharos", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30a", "question": "What is the Fahrenheit equivalent of -40 degrees Celsius", "answer": "-40 degrees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4eac106d333868d34d75c", "question": "What was the first Nazi concentration camp?", "answer": "Dachau (Nohra opened in March 1933 as a re-education center. Dachau opened after and became a model for future death camps and is considered to be the first)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab96cb86faa38a764be524", "question": "Which car company did Christian von Koenigsegg found in 1994?", "answer": "Koenigsegg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7d", "question": "Freetown is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Sierra Leone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede2d96ce05a3942286dce", "question": "Who wrote, sang, and played the instruments for \"Wonderful Christmastime\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b5c901dd7bf43be5e7d5", "question": "What sporting event is referred to as \"The Run for the Roses\"?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d52", "question": "What Herman Melville character always answers \"I would prefer not to\" whenever his boss asks him to work?", "answer": "Bartleby the Scrivener", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3f", "question": "In what key is Johann Pachelbel's famous \"Canon\"?", "answer": "D", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b311", "question": "Peter the Great is considered the founding father of what country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339804", "question": "What movie soundtrack is Eric Clapton's \"Tears in Heaven\" from?", "answer": "Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96fc323c87fd04dd15e45", "question": "What are the earliest known Christmas tree decorations?", "answer": "Apples", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b87561d8c1817608d53e8", "question": "Why does cheddar cheese need a bandage?", "answer": "It\u2019s aged longer -- Instead of wax, a bandage made of cloth is used to help the cheese \"breathe\" while it's in long-term storage.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f67", "question": "What does \"Alma mater\" translate to in English?", "answer": "Bountiful mother", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015fbc6fe83fe1f2a824c3c", "question": "What's the name given to the unleavened bread that is consumed at Passover?", "answer": "Matzoh, which symbolizes the fact the Israelites were in such a hurry when they escaped, they did not have time for bread to rise.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339317", "question": "In the film \"Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl\", the way Johnny Depp portrays Jack Sparrow was inspired by whom?", "answer": "Keith Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8f", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"The Door in the Floor\" based on?", "answer": "A Widow for One Year", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ed", "question": "What element makes your pee smell after you eat asparagus?", "answer": "Sulfur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b777", "question": "Julia Child, known as \"The French Chef\", was born in what country?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac60", "question": "Which carved stone was the key to the understanding of Egyptian hieroglyphics?", "answer": "The Rosetta Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7e", "question": "What year did the US issue a patent on the production of margarine?", "answer": "1871", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a772", "question": "What is the official state animal of Wisconsin?", "answer": "Badger", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c4", "question": "The opera Aida was commissioned to mark what event?", "answer": "Opening of the Khedivial Opera House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893f", "question": "Which of the Three Tenors set up his own competition for young singers in 1982?", "answer": "Luciano Pavarotti", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358e1d5db0d66a186cb566", "question": "During the 1990\u2019s who recorded the albums \"Out of Time\" and \"New Adventures in Hi-Fi\"?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69c6520565ad31a57c76b", "question": "Who was the first African-American to be featured on a U.S. postage stamp?", "answer": "Booker T. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e31", "question": "In the nursery rhyme \"This Little Piggy\", what meat did the third little piggy eat?", "answer": "Roast beef", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec9", "question": "\"Dig 'em Frog\" was the mascot for which Kellogg's breakfast cereal?", "answer": "Honey Smacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e39306d333868d34d72d", "question": "Which city served as the capital of the Ottoman Empire?", "answer": "Constantinople", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab1a", "question": "What European country is the Arch of Hadrian located in?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d98c308b8581f80b092b0", "question": "Approximately how much was the price of a single Bitcoin on January 1, 2017?", "answer": "$1,000 USD", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d06ad1a1c922dd1ac64ae", "question": "What's the official state sport of Alaska?", "answer": "Dog mushing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b1e6e662d71a53650fd5", "question": "The Uffizi museum can be found in which city?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07c", "question": "What WWII general was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec24148dc25ca9e12ef635", "question": "Whose concerts formed the basis of the documentary film \"Rattle and Hum\"?", "answer": "U2's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03e", "question": "What is the fear of social situations called?", "answer": "Sociophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b46801dd7bf43be5e7bf", "question": "What Marvel superhero was created to sell orange juice?", "answer": "Captain Citrus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa10", "question": "What is the capital of Gambia?", "answer": "Banjul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049ec7cf93664eb10486b5", "question": "Dogteeth tetras are a family of freshwater fishes native to what continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5b", "question": "What Broadway great's daughter wrote the book \"Freaky Friday\"?", "answer": "Richard Rodgers'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb4", "question": "Which famous number was dreaded by people in Orwell\u2019s 1984?", "answer": "101", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde2", "question": "What Georgetown star was the first player to be chosen by an NBA draft lottery winner?", "answer": "Patrick Ewing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84a", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find hepatocytes?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133932b", "question": "What Star Trek actor had a leading role in the show \"Boston Legal\"?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fe", "question": "Alnitak, Alnilam, and Mintaka are the three stars that make up what constellation's \"belt\"?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d43", "question": "Which Claude Monet painting is attributed to giving the Impressionist Movement its name?", "answer": "Impression, Sunrise", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef8", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Isabel Archer?", "answer": "The Portrait of a Lady", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600242584be4723ccac22184", "question": "Author Daniel Handler is best known for his children\u2019s books published under which pseudonym?", "answer": "Lemony Snicket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad1", "question": "What is the nickname for Rome, Italy?", "answer": "Eternal City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a141", "question": "Rod Stewart's second album was called after which alley?", "answer": "Gasoline Alley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99bbc21a8909e5c332d2f", "question": "What novel was the 1988 film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Who Censored Roger Rabbit?", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971dfa389261e916c8e09a9", "question": "Including special characters, how many letters are there in the German alphabet?", "answer": "Thirty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb8e67e83c707845b2136", "question": "What is the longest snake in the world?", "answer": "Reticulated python", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc95", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Peloton\"?", "answer": "Cycling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c3", "question": "Which videgame franchise had frequent segments on The Super Mario Bros. Super Show?", "answer": "The Legend of Zelda", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbae7ab0738315b1fb74e26", "question": "What mathematician published \"Elements\" and influenced the study of modern geometry?", "answer": "Euclid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c821", "question": "The constellation Sagittarius is usually depicted as aiming its arrow at what fierce neighbor?", "answer": "Scorpio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2db", "question": "What do ladybugs feed on during hibernation?", "answer": "Stored fat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d1", "question": "Who are the creators of the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Matt Stone and Trey Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d4d22b42d4a3561a9efc", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", which employee of Mrs. Parker was framed with stealing $850,000 from Senator Chalmers?", "answer": "Samantha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa3f86ce05a3942286eae", "question": "What song does Tom Cruise lip-sync to in his underwear in \"Risky Business\"?", "answer": "\"Old Time Rock & Roll\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd89", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Megalon?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b73", "question": "Who played the villain Howard Payne in the 1994 movie \"Speed\"?", "answer": "Dennis Hopper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f22", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the concertmaster?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c1", "question": "For what occassion did George Frideric Handel compose the anthem \"Zadok the Priest\"?", "answer": "Coronation of King George II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899bb860d398dc9cf7a6a0", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the Pelican State?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a3", "question": "What agricultural crop is Cuba's main export?", "answer": "Sugar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a162", "question": "Kappelkoff is the real surname of which actress?", "answer": "Doris Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d1155b4fea7fe947a22265", "question": "What year did Arthur Hailey publish the novel \"The Moneychangers\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5f", "question": "Who played Will on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Eric McCormack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971e13a89261e916c8e09b2", "question": "What alien species is affected by the Genophage in the Mass Effect Series?", "answer": "Krogan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b35301dd7bf43be5e7ac", "question": "What was the first video game played in space?", "answer": "Tetris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000f14a9a72b906b34e3d03", "question": "What kind of animal is a bantam?", "answer": "Chicken -- A true bantam is a breed of chicken that is naturally small.  The male has a reputation for being very aggressive.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f0", "question": "In which hemisphere is the Tropic of Cancer located?", "answer": "Northern", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec24e48dc25ca9e12ef63c", "question": "In Greek Mythology, the Oneiroi, were various gods and demigods that ruled over what?", "answer": "Dreams and nightmares", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca4", "question": "What is the heating element in Hasbro's Easy-Bake Oven\"?", "answer": "A lightbulb", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b7", "question": "What are categorized as the biological class \"aves\"?", "answer": "Birds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015fcaefe83fe1f2a824c43", "question": "At the age of 16, Saint Patrick was kidnapped by pirates. What work did his captors force him to do?", "answer": "They made him tend and rear animals", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a5535d3e1c6f9840ba31a3", "question": "Who won the 1990 Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Mikhail Gorbachev", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5901dcfd709c1c34536e6eb7", "question": "On Saturday Night Live, who played the recurring character known as \"Samurai Futaba\"?", "answer": "John Belushi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8d", "question": "What did Benjamin Franklin do on April 17, 1790?", "answer": "He died", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3f11c73aa70ea0b70afb", "question": "Which Italian region is the source of Marsala wine?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c1", "question": "On what continent would you find the Great Victoria Desert?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef2ede6ce05a3942286dfd", "question": "When did Vladimir Lenin serve as the head of the Soviet Russia?", "answer": "1917 to 1922", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133965b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the Springfield Elementary lunchlady?", "answer": "Doris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb69f05dad637d903c884c", "question": "Which country has the oldest continuously used national flag?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f74a6a9e54d890926f6fc", "question": "It was illegal for women to wear what in 19th century Florence?", "answer": "Buttons", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7e", "question": "How many red squares are there on a standard checker board?", "answer": "32", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937e9a508d98002fdd6339b", "question": "Who is Donald Duck's girlfriend?", "answer": "Daisy Duck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8aa", "question": "In what city would you find the Golden Gate Park?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ca", "question": "What is the largest island in the Atlantic?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60137138138175489539638a", "question": "What nationality is Sir Anthony Hopkins?", "answer": "Welsh-American -- Born in Wales, he was naturalized an American citizen on April 12, 2000.\u00a0He maintains is British citizenship.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3a", "question": "Which of the TV's \"Golden Girls\" plays the title character in \"Stop! Or My Mom Will Shoot\"?", "answer": "Estelle Getty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c408", "question": "A \"scarlet runner\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Plant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c914", "question": "What is the atomic number of magnesium?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3a", "question": "Which basketball superstar had a major role in the 1996 movie \"Space Jam\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339299", "question": "What is the main difference between the character Starbuck in the 70's version of \"Battlestar Galact", "answer": "Starbuck is a female in the reboot and a male in the 70's version", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242374be4723ccac22182", "question": "Which leading English poet of was killed in action during World War I one week before the end of the war?", "answer": "Wilfred Owen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd6bbe347d002c297e4bc", "question": "Morten Harket is the lead singer of which band?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc100e469bb8041d07a06b", "question": "In 1917 a bakery in Chattanooga, Tennessee introduced what popular Southern treat?", "answer": "MoonPie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e88", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Iris in \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ee", "question": "What does a Scoville unit measure?", "answer": "Spiciness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339735", "question": "In which decade was the first electric guitar made?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d5", "question": "How many children did poet Sylvia Plath have?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e8b806d333868d34d74d", "question": "Which monarch has a place named after them on every continent?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd69", "question": "According to the 1940s jingle, after what two men pitched did Boston Braves fans \"pray for rain\"?", "answer": "Spahn and Sain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008cbecf842fa4c4ba96a1", "question": "What is a community of ants called?", "answer": "Colony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b269", "question": "Artist Bono shared Time's \"Man of the Year\" honors with what other man and his wife?", "answer": "Bill Gates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33e", "question": "Archbishop Makarios of Cyprus was exiled in 1956 to where?", "answer": "The Seychelles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc4", "question": "What jazz legend's singing shattered the glass in the famous \"Is it live or is it Memorex?\" ads?", "answer": "Ella Fitzgerald's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ecfefe83fe1f2a824c06", "question": "How many times are Jews supposed to wash their hands at the Seder table?", "answer": "Two times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338897", "question": "What drug did Sherlock Holmes take at the start of his career?", "answer": "Cocaine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adad", "question": "What is the real first name of the former First Lady known as Lady Bird Johnson?", "answer": "Claudia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d99", "question": "What author created the character of Uncle Tom?", "answer": "Harriet Beecher Stowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b339", "question": "What replaced English as the official language of Kenya in 1974?", "answer": "Swahili", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b599", "question": "Which artist's song was the 10 billionth iTunes download?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b8", "question": "Who directed the 1980 movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "John Landis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2d", "question": "Captain James Cook made how many voyages to the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "3", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983b", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his portrayal of an aging pool shark in the movie \"The Color of Money\"?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b382", "question": "Is kissing under the mistletoe comes from whose customs?", "answer": "Druids", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5c", "question": "During what decade did the twist become the big dance craze?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22c", "question": "Where did Al Capone spend the majority of his 1931 sentence for tax evasion?", "answer": "Alcatraz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600781fabd51d85e222ab651", "question": "What is the title of Henri Matisse's famous portrait of his wife?", "answer": "In 1905, just prior to such works being derisively labeled as the creations of Les Fauves, he painted\u00a0\"The Green Stripe\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600244334be4723ccac221a0", "question": "What famous artist was considered a suspect in the 1911 theft of the Mona Lisa?", "answer": "Pablo Picasso\u00a0was arrested and questioned along with avant-garde poet and playwright Guillaume Apollinaire. Both were cleared.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339510", "question": "Who played Molly's love interest in the movie \"Pretty in Pink\"?", "answer": "Andrew McCarthy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a8", "question": "When was Coca-Cola first introduced?", "answer": "1886", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fd", "question": "Who was the only bare-footed Beatle on the Abbey Road album cover?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017375e44491cbd7c5a1789", "question": "Who designed and built the interior structure of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The innovative designer and builder Gustave Eiffel and his structural engineer, Maurice Koechlin designed and built the statue.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69e9120565ad31a57c786", "question": "During World War II who was known as \"The Butcher of Prague\"?", "answer": "Reinhard Heydrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cb7e877e98cb97778a1c", "question": "Which country's Easter brunch typically includes a ryemeal soup known as zurek?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb1", "question": "Who installed the first Archbishop of Canterbury in 597 AD?", "answer": "Pope Gregory l", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7be6a2b316f4693fb6790", "question": "Sweet potatoes are commonly but mistakenly sold under what name?", "answer": "Yams (However, real yams are a completely different vegetable, with a brown bark-like skin and a starchy flavor.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be5", "question": "What year did Johnny Depp receive his Hollywood Walk of Fame star in?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd5ff70499cffc60b84237", "question": "Apart from the toga, what was the main article of Roman fashion?", "answer": "Tunic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc46f6de0eb824d4052f3", "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd5aa7e83c707845b2164", "question": "What was the name of the whale in the 1993 movie, \"Free Willy\"?", "answer": "Keiko", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a21b12f2a7826b9b8718", "question": "What sport would you be playing if the score was deuce?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015de8bfe83fe1f2a824b6d", "question": "What general during the American Revolutionary War fought for the American Continental Army but defected to the British Army?", "answer": "Benedict Arnold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ad", "question": "Which is the largest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23c", "question": "Who released the album \"Madman Across the Water\" in 1971?", "answer": "Elton John\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bfc", "question": "Which character did Mickey Rooney play in the movie \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\"?", "answer": "Mr. Yunioshi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b124", "question": "Which war included an infantry assault known as Pickett's Charge?", "answer": "American Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8f", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Bedrock?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338989", "question": "Who conducted the Philadelphia Orchestra and shook hands with Mickey Mouse in \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Leopold Stokowski", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c193", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597de01177980686f722d188", "question": "The word \"Sandwich\" is a reference to which 18th century English aristocrat?", "answer": "John Montagu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da6", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Superman II\"?", "answer": "E. G. Marshall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f43d01dd7bf43be5e820", "question": "TBD stands for what?", "answer": "To Be Determined", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ed", "question": "What was Daniel's last name in 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "LaRusso", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a24c9d816e292245c14", "question": "Who painted \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Salvador Dal\u00ed -- \"The Persistence of Memory,\" aka \"The Melting Watches,\" is one of Dali's most recognizable works.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10e", "question": "What type of alcoholic drink is Manzanilla?", "answer": "Sherry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b048", "question": "In what year did Lewis & Clark depart St. Louis to begin their expedition to the west?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba1a6874c93a3298b2129", "question": "What year did Jimmy Carter assume office as the 39th President of the United States?", "answer": "1977", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ef", "question": "What language does the word \"algebra\" come from?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab9f", "question": "On which river does Saint. Petersburg lie?", "answer": "Neva River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14f", "question": "What city do Batman and Robin patrol?", "answer": "Gotham City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b55f", "question": "What was the first soft drink to be consumed in outer space?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b793", "question": "In \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the fifth day?", "answer": "Five gold rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8af5ec223966ae8f8835", "question": "In what book of the Bible did the prison warden find Andy's rock hammer in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Exodus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd2", "question": "Who designed Richard Gere's wardrobe in the movie \"American Gigolo\"?", "answer": "Giorgio Armani", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22a", "question": "Whittaker Chambers hid Alger Hiss' purloined State Department documents in a hollowed-out what?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c239", "question": "On what holiday did Harry Houdini die in 1926?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7147a9e54d890926f6dd", "question": "The second highest mountain on land is K2.  What does the letter \"K\" stand for?", "answer": "Karakoram -- K2 is located in the Karakoram Mountain Range.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010ca1f0775fa611bce67f3", "question": "What Apple computer was named after Steve Jobs' daughter?", "answer": "Lisa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3eafe38e4e5d4832e6317", "question": "Which company produced the World War II fighter plane \"Spitfire\"?", "answer": "Triumph", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8f", "question": "What does \"J.R.R.\" stand for in J.R.R. Tolkien's name?", "answer": "John Ronald Reuel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c996877e98cb977789f7", "question": "Which city is known as the Glass Capital of the World?", "answer": "Toledo, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067dbfff9c0647b50a8073", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339884", "question": "In Disney's \"Aladdin\", what is the name of Jasmine's pet tiger?", "answer": "Rajah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a93620565ad31a57c7ff", "question": "John Henry \"Doc\" Holliday died as a result of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339648", "question": "What was the nickname of Gene Hackman's character in The French Connection?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae864587f28483af1e7fdce", "question": "How many countries share common borders with India?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b36ae662d71a53650fdf", "question": "Which famous composer continued working as he lost his hearing?", "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971df3a89261e916c8e09a7", "question": "How is the groundnut better known?", "answer": "The peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b7ab9676490a8cc1a6e5290", "question": "What is the SI unit for electrical capacitance?", "answer": "Farad", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccd", "question": "What line is missing from some bowdlerized edits of Van Morrison's \"Brown Eyed Girl\"?", "answer": "Making love in the green field", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a538cf93664eb10486c9", "question": "Including spin-offs and tie-ins, how many issues were released as part of the original \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic series before its planned end in 2007?", "answer": "106", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c871", "question": "What two elements make up water?", "answer": "Hydrogen and oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392af", "question": "What pop star's fans are known as \"Claymates\"?", "answer": "Clay Aiken's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339948", "question": "What young actor played Forrest's son in the movie \"Forrest  Gump\"?", "answer": "Haley Joel Osment", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf0", "question": "What fitness program did Judi Sheppard Missett create in 1969?", "answer": "Jazzercise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339777", "question": "Why must Leonard tattoo notes on himself and take polaroids in the film \"Memento\"?", "answer": "He has no short-term memory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa6206ce05a3942286ecb", "question": "In which city does the film \"Home Alone 2\" take place?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c35a7815febcc896f925e", "question": "In which country would you most likely find the traditional Mariachi bands?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5902a120cad1ec93f27df773", "question": "What 1960\u2019s film with Michael Caine is often credited with aiding to the popularity of the French Press?", "answer": "The Ipcress File", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339275", "question": "On the TV show \"Next Iron Chef\", Celine Tio was eliminated how many episodes before the finale?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb08768cf631c2414a13b57", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what are the three names of Daenerys\u2019 dragons?", "answer": "Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c760", "question": "What Greek physician is known as \"The Father of Medicine\"?", "answer": "Hippocrates", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3f", "question": "In 1988, who were admitted at Wheaton College for the first time?", "answer": "Men", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c17", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the third plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Lice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b699285e762b54eb9be9423", "question": "What is the technical term for a 20-sided die?", "answer": "Icosahedron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc143ec223966ae8f8867", "question": "In 1908, boxer Jack Johnson became the first African-American to do what?", "answer": "Win the heavyweight title", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338879", "question": "What is the literary term for a play on words?", "answer": "Pun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4e", "question": "The anniversary of the death of what magician is recognized as National Magic Day in the US?", "answer": "Harry Houdini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3f", "question": "Eliot Ness is best known for his fight against organized crime in what city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339285", "question": "The alliance \"Chilltown\" consists of what two players?", "answer": "Dr. Will and Mike Boogie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f122ff048f679a45aaae", "question": "Zoophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Animals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c317", "question": "What does the abbreviation USB stand for?", "answer": "Universal Serial Bus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc09", "question": "What high civilian Indian award was Mother Teresa awarded?", "answer": "Bharat Ratna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eaea6f83302ff91e4648b", "question": "In TV, what does SCTV stand for?", "answer": "Second City Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f72c73aa70ea0b70b00", "question": "\"Oro y Plata\" (Gold and Silver) is the motto for which U.S. state?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac85", "question": "What was banned in Mississippi in 1907 that didn't become legal there again until 1966?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c089", "question": "Wanamaker's of Philadelphia first US store to install what in 1878?", "answer": "Electric illumination", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff6", "question": "Sakhmet was the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War and healing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60c", "question": "Entomologists study what?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a626", "question": "Which is the westernmost state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59524476736d4be723796b69", "question": "What city did Lando Calrissian live in in \"Star Wars V: The Empire Strikes Back\"?", "answer": "Cloud City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaaa47e83c707845b20e0", "question": "Alektorophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Chickens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a953661d1b4d384d5d676", "question": "Which dinosaur got its name because scientists thought that it fed on eggs?", "answer": "Oviraptor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf56", "question": "Which type of prepared bread is named after an opera singer?\u00a0", "answer": "Melba Toast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46f", "question": "Which politician is known as Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bae", "question": "What was the last name of the main family on the TV show \"3rd Rock From the Sun\"?", "answer": "Solomon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a552c03e1c6f9840ba319d", "question": "Which Asian country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49d", "question": "Why were the 1916 Olympic Games cancelled?", "answer": "Due to World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399cf", "question": "What famous blind musician has the real given last name Judkins?", "answer": "Stevie Wonder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b607", "question": "What is \"Sheffield Wednesday\"?", "answer": "A soccer team", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65c401f3c0ead6880d610", "question": "In the Bible, who was the coppersmith that did Paul much evil?", "answer": "Alexander", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924c", "question": "What do the thieves set out to steal in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs?\"", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ee", "question": "According to the 1973 movie, soylent green is what?", "answer": "People", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3674ff048f679a45ab0e", "question": "What vegetable grows fast enough that you can hear it?", "answer": "Rhubarb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a495", "question": "Which Australian state borders all other mainland states?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b477", "question": "What year did Arthur W. Savage patent the radial tire?", "answer": "1915", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b370a81c3f17ccc40c8e17", "question": "Pubs are said to have evolved from what Anglo-Saxon establishment that started to appear in the 5th century?", "answer": "Alehouses", "category": "History"}, {"id": "5fe7cdd2877e98cb97778a3b", "question": "Which country is the largest producer of vanilla?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc89", "question": "What NHL team's theme music is Aram Khachaturian's most famous composition?", "answer": "The Buffalo Sabres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a29620565ad31a57c7ae", "question": "Who was the first US presidential candidate to speak at a political convention?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e93d17ccba3ffe45786ca", "question": "What was Buddy Holly's real first name?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a8", "question": "What cheese is served with a classic Greek salad?", "answer": "Feta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5c", "question": "In terms of decibels, what is normally the loudest instrument in a symphony orchestra?", "answer": "Trombone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb2af65ff7d326b622a77", "question": "Mycophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e7", "question": "What is the longest insect?", "answer": "The walking stick", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdabd210b8cce1e6fda7061", "question": "What is the body of the DMC DeLorean car made out of?", "answer": "Stainless steel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a75", "question": "What Irish author wrote the 1938 novel \"Murphy\"?", "answer": "Samuel Beckett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe734f2eec85e375820b240", "question": "What prison held Rudolf Hess after World War II?", "answer": "Spandau Prison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971c", "question": "In \"The Addams Family\", what does Morticia do that always excites Gomez?", "answer": "Speaks French", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339276", "question": "What movie stars Adam Sandler and Drew Barrymore and takes place in Hawaii?", "answer": "50 First Dates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990afb4b72eedf883a8c709", "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?", "answer": "Strait of Gibraltar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b415", "question": "How did UN Secretary General Dag Hammarskj\u00f6ld die in September, 1961?", "answer": "In a plane crash", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94f", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Mickey Mantle play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c603", "question": "Which planet is named for the God of War?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd4a", "question": "By US law, exit signs in buildings must be one of what two colors?", "answer": "Red or green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c2", "question": "Which Amendment to the US Constitution gave women the right to vote?", "answer": "19th", "category": "history"}]